<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MP&#39;s Projects and Papers</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MP&#39;s Projects and Papers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:01:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematica Steps to Latex [Beta]</title>
      <link>/post/simulation/mathematica-steps-to-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:01:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/simulation/mathematica-steps-to-latex/</guid>
      <description>A common problem when using Mathematica to derive expressions is similar to a big problem plaguing machine learning algorithms today: It is difficult or impossible to explain the result due to the internal complexity of the black-box which generates it.
Mathematica&amp;rsquo;s internal algorithms for performing various symbolic computation are built for speed, not simplicity, and in many cases the method Mathematica uses is nothing like the manual way humans would find the solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quadtree Particle Simulation</title>
      <link>/post/simulation/quadtree-particle-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 13:59:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/simulation/quadtree-particle-simulation/</guid>
      <description>A small particle simulation was written in JS, utilizing a simplified (constant depth) quadtree structure. The model includes forces between nearby particles, so rather than invoke a O(n^2) operation to compute the net force for each particle, a quadtree is used so each particle may efficiently access its neighbors.
The forces used are tuned to provide some amount of clustering, but also to provide global homogeneity to prevent too many particles appearing in one quadtree section (which would decrease cpu-time efficiency).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 12:14:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can contact me using the below form. If it&amp;rsquo;s more convenient, I can also be contacted on Github or LinkedIn.
 f = (s) = {return s.replace(/[a-zA-Z]/g,function(c){return String.fromCharCode((c=(c=c.charCodeAt(0)+13)?c:c-26);});} window.onload = () = {document.getElementById(&#34;contact-form&#34;).action += f(&#34;zr@zcbgr.ng&#34;)};  Your Email
Your Name
Message

 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Pendulum</title>
      <link>/post/simulation/double-pendulum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 20:58:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/simulation/double-pendulum/</guid>
      <description>This is a simulation of 2 bobs, connected by massless, perfectly rigid rods to a central pivot under the force of uniform gravity. In addition to being the motivating example for chaotic systems (in addition to the Lorenz system, its fluid mechanics counterpart), the double pendulum represents some interesting challenges.
   Draw circle bounds Draw cherry tracer Draw connections Pause Clear cherry tracer
Simulation parameters:
Angle 1
Angle 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oriented Bounding-Box Heuristic</title>
      <link>/post/bioinformatics/oriented-bounding-box-heuristic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 20:35:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bioinformatics/oriented-bounding-box-heuristic/</guid>
      <description>The 2-dimensional minimum-area oriented bounding box problem is as follows: Given a set of coplanar points, how can we efficiently find the smallest rectangle which encloses these points? Additionally, that rectangle can be oriented at any angle with respect to the coordinate system.
One interesting estimate for the solution, which guarantees &amp;ldquo;pretty good&amp;rdquo; results in O(n) time is a natural extension of orthogonal linear regression. Specifically, we assume that the minimum rectangle is aligned to the orthogonal &amp;ldquo;line of best fit&amp;rdquo; of the point set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Presidential Luncheon</title>
      <link>/post/life/2019-presidential-luncheon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 18:58:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/life/2019-presidential-luncheon/</guid>
      <description>This last Wednesday I had the honor of attending a luncheon with ODU&amp;rsquo;s current president John R. Broderick. This event was a meetup with the local Tau Beta Pi engineering honor society chapter.
The food was delicious! We were able to talk to Broderick about current events on campus, and suggestions we had (especially with regard to on-campus parking).
Group photo included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Dimensional Linear Regression</title>
      <link>/post/bioinformatics/one-dimensional-linear-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 18:27:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bioinformatics/one-dimensional-linear-regression/</guid>
      <description>The simple linear regression algorithm is a closed-form solution to a least-squared distance minimization problem. Here is demonstrated the one-dimensional case of simple linear regression.
 $$ \min_{\alpha,\beta} \sum_{i=1}^{n} (y_i - \alpha - \beta x_i)^2 $$  Click and drag the black points to affect the regression. Double click to add or remove points. The blue point in the center represents the geometric average, through which the fit always passes through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quadratic Bezier Curves</title>
      <link>/post/bioinformatics/quadratic-bezier-curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 17:40:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bioinformatics/quadratic-bezier-curves/</guid>
      <description>Quadratic Bézier curves are explicit parametric functions of the following form:
 $$ x(t) = (1-t)^2 x_0 + 2t(1-t) x_1 + t^2 x_2\\ y(t) = (1-t)^2 y_0 + 2t(1-t) y_1 + t^2 y_2\\ t \in \mathbb R[0,1] $$  These curves are perhaps the simplest class of parametric curves, but useful in their own right. This is a small demo of such curves.
Drag the control points around to see the curve change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 17:28:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/</guid>
      <description>You can find abstracts, figures, citations and more at my ResearchGate profile.
 Tunazzina Islam, Michael Poteat, Jing He, &amp;ldquo;Quantification of Twist from the Central Lines of β-strands&amp;rdquo;, Journal of Computational Biology, January 2018, 25 (1): 114-120
 Poteat, M., He, J. &amp;ldquo;Modeling Beta-sheets using Iterative Bezier Surface Fitting on Cryo-EM Density Maps&amp;rdquo;, Molecular Based Mathematical Biology, Apr 2017; 5:31–39
 Tunazzina Islam, Michael Poteat, Jing He, &amp;ldquo;Analysis of ß-strand Twist from the 3-dimensional Image of a Protein&amp;rdquo;, Computational Structural Bioinformatics Workshop 2017 in conjunction with ACM-BCB 2017, Pages 650-654.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 16:24:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, I&amp;rsquo;m Michael Poteat and this is my online portfolio and blog, where I broadcast and archive personal projects I work on, and discuss/post things I find interesting online.
I work as a graduate research assistant at Old Dominion University. My current topic of research is LTL (linear-temporal logic) and its application for monitoring and verification of mission correctness in autonomous robotics. As well, some future research planned will include utilization of machine learning to produce temporal models that detect adverse operational conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>